Graf, Oskar Marie; Papers ger002
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria Graf, 1919-1967; 4; 378 file folders
  - Unpublished novels, 1913-1935; Undated; 4.2
    - "Mir geht nichts über mich", Undated (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 71)
      Exposé.
    - Neue Deutsche Blätter, 1934-1935 (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 72)
      Photocopy of title page, naming Graf as co-editor.
  - Essays, stories, 1919-1978; 4.3
    Dates reflect publication date of clipping.
    - "Aber viel ist wenig", 1963; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 73)
    - "Much is but little" ("Aber viel ist wenig"). English, Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 74)
    - "Der Albtraum", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 75)
    - "Alles ist eitel", 1933; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 76)
    - "Alois Metzenbachers Menschenwerdung" ("Die denkwürdigste Periode in Leben"), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 77)
    - "Als Bayer in Amerika" / "Made in Amerika", Undated; typescripts, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 78)
    - "Der alte Dichter. Eine Weihnachtsgeschichte", Undated; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 79)
    - "Am Abend besuchen", 1968; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 80)
    - "Asbach Uralt", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 81)
    - "Auch ein Emigrant. Erzählung" ("Emigrant Joseph Lochner", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 82)
    - "Auch ein Trinkspruch", 1967; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 83)
    - "Auch Gaffen macht sich bezahlt" / "Gaffer wollen ertragen sein", 1973; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 84)
    - "Auf den Beweis hin, musste er sitzen", 1974; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 85)
    - "Die Aufgabe der kommenden Kunst", 1919; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 86)
    - "Aus einem Brief", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 87)
    - "Aus unbekannten Motiven", 1974; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 88)
    - "Baberlababb...! Ein Märchen, das Schulkindern gefällt", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 89)
    - "Der barbarische Nationalismus. Zur deutschen Bücherverbrennung 1933", 1973; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 90)
    - "Die Bärenwirtin weiss zu antworten", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 91)
    - "Baroness Lies", 1964; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 92)
    - "Bauernfroemmigkeit" / "Echte Froemmigkeit", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 93)
    - "Bayrische Selbsthilfe", 1933; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 94)
    - "Begegnung mit Hitler (1933)", 1978; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 95)
    - "Begegnung mit Rilke", 1975; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 96)
    - "Der beste General, den ich kannte", 1963; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 97)
    - "Die betrogene Worte", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 98)
    - "The Revolt of the Words. A Fantasy" ("Die betrogene Worte"), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 99)
    - "Bilgerius Wild, seligen Angedenkens" / "Der keusche Bilgerius Wild", 1964; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 100)
    - "Bill sagt Nein", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 101)
    - "On his own" ("Bill sagt Nein"), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 102)
    - "Das bittere Hemmnis", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 103)
    - "Chefredaktion der NBI", 1964; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 104)
    - "Dein unbekannter Bruder", Undated; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 105)
    - "Deutsche Schriftsteller in Amerika", 1939; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 106)
    - "Dichter der 'Offenen Welt'. Zur 100. Wiederkehr des Geburtstags von Rainer Maria Rilke", 1975; typescript, clippings (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 107)
    - "Die vom Büro" / "Die Angestellte", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 108)
    - "Ein glückliches Mädchen", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 109)
    - "Ein handgreiflicher Beweis", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 100)
    - "Ein objektiver Mensch. Erinnerung an Bertolt Brecht", Undated; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 111)
    - "Ein Retter in der Not", 1972; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 112)
    - "Ein Wollknäuel als Lebensretter", 1964; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 113)
    - "Der Einbruch. Eine wahre Dorfgeschichte", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 114)
    - "Eine Oktoberfest-Geschichte", 1965; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 115)
    - "Des Einen Tod" ("Der Konkurrent"), 1952; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 116)
    - "Einiges zum Abschied von München 1964", clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 117)
    - "Entscheidende Kleinigkeiten", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 118)
    - "Das Ereignis", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 119)
    - "Erinnerung an einen vielgeliebten Raunzer", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 120)
    - "Die erloesten Baecker. Ein Maerchen aus der Lutherzeit", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 121)
    - "God Almighty and the bakers" ("Die erlösten Bäcker"), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 122)
    - "Erste Begegnung mit dem jungen Brecht", 1962; typescript, clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 123)
    - "First Encounter of Berthold [!] Brecht and Oskar Maria Graf" ("Erste Begegnung mit dem jungen Brecht"), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 124)
    - "Das erwachsene Gewissen", 1933; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 125)
    - "Etwas wie ein 'Antlitz'", 1964; clipping (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 126)
    - "Feigheit macht gefährlich", Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 127)
    - "Die Feuertaufe" / "Man heisst uns Menschen", Undated; typescripts (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 128)
    - "Baptism of Fire" ("Die Feuertaufe"), Undated; typescript (Box 6 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 129)
    - "Die Flucht" / "Die ersten Tage des Exils", Undated; typescripts (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 1)
    - "Der Flüchtling. Eine sonderbare Nachtgeschichte", 1953; clippings (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 2)
    - "Frauen". Statements on women and love, Undated; typescripts, miscellaneous (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 3)
    - "Gegen und für den Fremdenverkehr", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 4)
    - "Gesinnung ist kein lehrer Wahn", 1933; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 5)
    - "Der Gespenstertoni kuriert einen Hausdrachen", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 6)
    - "Gespräche mit dem Vater über Ideale", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 7)
    - "Goethe im Dritten Reich", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 8)
    - "Der goldene Knopf. Ein Kindermaerchen", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 9)
    - "Grenzen der Dummheit", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 10)
    - "H. M. Davringhausen", 1924; clipping (excerpt) (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 11)
    - "Der Haunigl", 1977; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 12)
    - "Die Hauptperson wird vorgestellt", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 13)
    - "Heil Hitler", 1933; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 14)
    - "Die heilige Landstrasse. Ein Märchen für törichte Mütter", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 15)
    - "Die Heilquelle", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 16)
    - "Das Himmelreich der ewigen Hochzeiten", 1933; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 17)
    - "Die Höchtlin", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 18)
    - "Ich bin Bert Brecht", 1968; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 19)
    - "Ihr lasst den Armen schuldig werden", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 20)
    - "Immer mit der Gemütlichkeit", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 21)
    - "In Sachen Brecht", 1962; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 22)
    - "Die Kampfleistung der deutschen antifaschistischen Schriftsteller", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 23)
    - "Das Katzerl. Eine bayrische Geschichte", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 24)
    - "Kinder macht kein Theater!", 1933; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 25)
    - "Das 'Kommunistenstückl' von Aining. Ein wahres Begebnis aus dem jetzigen Bayern", 1933; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 26)
    - "Der Konkurrent", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 27)
    - "Der Kramer-Jackl als Klaubauf", 1972; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 28)
    - "Die Kupfernatter", 1944; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 29)
    - "Der Lermoser-Michl hat Pech", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 30)
    - "Lustige Ergebnisse in der Weimarer Republik", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 31)
    - "Mach ma hoit a Revoluzion", 1968; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 32)
    - "Macht des Wortes", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 33)
    - "Das Märchen vom König", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 34)
    - "Maitage in München 1919", 1969; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 35)
    - "Man darf nichts glauben ...", 1963; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 36)
    - "Meine feuerpolizeiliche Dramaturgie. Eine Rencontre mit dem jungen Brecht", 1973; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 37)
    - "Der Mieder-Strauß", 1961; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 38)
    - "Der Mietvertrag" / "Die puenktliche Mieterin", 1966; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 39)
    - "Der missbrauchte erste April", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 40)
    - "Der missglückte Schwur", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 41)
    - "Der Mond rebelliert. Ein Märchen aus unserer Zeit", 1967; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 42)
    - "The Moon Rebels. A Fable of Our Times" ("Der Mond rebelliert"), Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 43)
    - "Der Mord im Wimbacher Forst", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 44)
    - "Muenchner Anekdoten", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 45)
    - "Der Nachschuß", 1964; clippings (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 46)
    - "Der nächstlilegende Gedanke", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 47)
    - "Nächtliche Ruhestörung", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 48)
    - "Naemlich Hinkefuss", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 49)
    - "Namely Lameleg" ("Naemlich Hindefuss"), Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 50)
    - "Der Neujahrsbrief", 1969; 1972 (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 51)
    - "Niemand und jeder. Eine Sinngeschichte", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 52)
    - "Oberammergauer Künstlerpech", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 53)
    - "Die Opfer sind stärker", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 54)
    - "Oskar Maria Graf erzählt:", 1929; Undated; clippings (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 55)
    - "Pech beim Herrgottsschnitzen", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 56)
    - "Die Perle der Treibjagd", 1933; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 57)
    - "Politisches", 1940; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 58)
    - "Die Predigt im Wirtshaus", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 59)
    - "Psyche. Ein Faschingserlebnis in Wien", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 60)
    - "Der Rat des Weisen. Eine Singeschichte fuer plumpe Liebhaber", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 61)
    - "Das Rätsel Nuschke", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 62)
    - "Die Reise nach Wasserburg oder Provinzschriftstellers Sommeridyll", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 63)
    - "Der rettende Vorschlag", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 64)
    - "Der Ring", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 65)
    - "Der Rocher-Peter rächt sich", 1933; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 66)
    - "Der Ruhm trügt", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 67)
    - "[Georg] Schrimpf und der Kommissar. Zum 50. Jahrestag der November-Revolution", 1968; typescript, clippings (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 68)
    - "Schweres Geschütz aufgefahren. Was der Hupfauerin passiert ist" / "Die Hupfauerin", 1968; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 69)
    - "Selbstdarstellungen deutscher Dichter: XII. Oskar Maria Graf", 1931; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 70)
    - "Seltsame Liebeswege. Eine oberbayerische Bauerngeschichte" / "Die Gewitterhochzeit", 1959; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 71)
    - "Seltsame Menschen", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 72)
    - "Das siegreiche Beispiel", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 73)
    - "Staatsmann Haunschild", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 74)
    - "Der Stärkere. Eine amerikanische Geschichte", 1940; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 75)
    - "Der Sturz ins Dunkel", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 76)
    - "Der Tod des Hasses", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 77)
    - "Der Tote im Wald" / "Der Mönch mit den Heiligenbildchen", 1963; 1973 (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 78)
    - "Träume, Leidenschaften, Farben. Zum 175. Geburtstag des malenden Genies Delacroix", 1973; clippings (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 79)
    - "Über antisemitische Ereignisse in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 80)
    - "Über Emigration", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 81)
    - "Über Ernst Toller", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 82)
    - "Um das Recht der Verfemten!", 1936; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 83)
    - "Das umständliche Attentat", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 84)
    - "'Und haettet die Sehnsucht nicht ....!' Eine fast wahre Geschichte", 1964; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 85)
    - "Das Unglück. Eine Künstlergeschichte", Undated; typescript. pc (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 86)
    - "Der unheimliche Nachbar. Eine New Yorker Geschichte", 1949?; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 87)
    - "My Uncanny Neighbour" ("Der unheimliche Nachbar"), Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 88)
    - "Uniformen ohne Vaterland", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 90)
    - "Das Vaterland a.D. Ein Maerchen ohne heutige Gueltigkeit", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 91)
    - "Verbrennt mich!", 1933; clippings (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 92)
    - "Burn Me!" ("Verbrennt mich!"), Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 93)
    - "Verbrennt mich!" References to the article, Undated (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 94)
    - "Der verpfuschte Christus", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 95)
    - "Der verpfuschte Hitler", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 96)
    - "Das verpfuschte Jubiläum. Eine lustige bayrische Dorfgeschichte aus heutiger Zeit", Undated; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 97)
    - "Das verpfuschte Theaterspiel" / "Ding oder Kind? Bericht eines verpfuschten Theaterspiels", 1973; typescript, clippings (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 98)
    - "Vom Lenzelter-Anderl seinem verpfuschten Sterben", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 99)
    - "Vom Sinn der Geschichte", 1978; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 100)
    - "Wand an Wand", 1959; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 101)
    - "Warum lebe ich nicht in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland", 1962; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 102)
    - "Was es mit dem Krieg auf sich hat", 1976; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 103)
    - "Wer ist der Pfiffigere?", 1933; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 104)
    - "Weswegen wir Gerichte haben ....", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 105)
    - "Die Wette", 1933; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 106)
    - "Die Wette im Himmel. Ein Maerchen", Undated; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 107)
    - "Die widerspenstige Erbe", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 108)
    - "Wie damals in meiner Kindheit -- Baierische Christmette in New York" / "Erinnerung an einen Mettengang", 1971; typescript, clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 109)
    - "Wie dem toten Haunzbauern das Maul schief geworden ist", Undated; typescript (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 110)
    - "Wie der Loisl mit der Mimi eine Bergtour machte. Eine oberbayerische Geschichte", 1962; clipping (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 111)
    - "Wie die Knechtschaft auf die Erde kam. Eine Legende", 1974; clippings (Box 7 (4-Published and unpublished writings of Oskar Maria ), Folder 112)